# **Daniel Sawyer**

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

#### **Profile**

Dedicated and experienced Civil Engineer with extensive knowledge of engineering principles, theories, specifications, and standards. Bringing leadership, drive, and over seven years of experience to the table. Proven track record of finishing complex projects under budget and ahead of schedule. Substantial knowledge and experience with environmentally sustainable construction.

### **Employment History**

#### Civil Engineer, Hexagon Corporation, Hartford

SEPTEMBER 2014 - SEPTEMBER 2019

- Carefully managed projects so that milestones were met during agreed time and within budget confines.
- Attended meetings to discuss projects with clients, contractors, asset owners, and stockholders.
- Created detailed plans and frequently monitored progress to assure project goals were met.
- Ensured that building regulations were all met and provided thorough directions with any unusual or difficult engineering issue.

#### Civil Engineer, Racon & Lewis Ltd, Danbury

AUGUST 2012 - AUGUST 2014

- Planned and directed the execution of various projects, keeping economical, administrative, and physical requirements in mind.
- Trained incoming engineers to meet standards and protocol expectations.
- Wrote daily reports for accountability and quality assurance.
- Advised project managers on financial decisions regarding product costs.

#### Junior Civil Engineer, Racon & Lewis Ltd, Danbury

AUGUST 2009 - AUGUST 2012

- Assisted senior engineers with any and all tasks related to related to ensuring project success.
- Inspected all materials to ensure project specifications and quantities properly met.
- Thoroughly inspected all major structures and supervised any revisions made.
- Monitored construction and inspected installation of major systems.
- Assisted with and independently produced many Engineer reports.

#### Education

#### Master of Civil Engineering, New York University, New York

JANUARY 2009 - JANUARY 2011

• Graduated with a 3.9 GPA.

#### Bachelor of Civil Engineering, Manhattan College, Riverdale

AUGUST 2005 - MAY 2009

- Graduated suma cum laude.
- President of the Engineer's Society.

#### **Details**

Tampa
United States
813-613-3984
daniel@danielsawyer.com

#### Links

Homepage

**GitHub** 

#### Skills

**Analytical Thinking Skills** 

Principles and Practices of Engineering

**Creative Problem Solving** 

Field Investigation Skills

Project Management

## References

Paula Franson from Racon & Lewis Ltd

pfranson@raconltd.com | 917-283-2288

John Cooke from Hexagon Corporation

jcooke@hexcorp.com | 212-317-2743

Jaunita Banks from Hexagon Ltd

jbanks@hexcorp.com | 212-317-2819